# MSc. Albi Dode

# Software Engineer & DPO

Hähnelstraße 23, 04177 Leipzig, Germany | +491638587648 | info@albidode.info

in linkedin.com/in/albidode albidode.info

## **Summary**

Software Engineer/Developer, IT support, Manual Tester, Technical Writer, and Data Protection Officer providing technical support, developing software programs, web sites, giving information security/DPO consulence. I have knowledge in Agile methodology for leading teams in achieving excellence in client satisfaction, productivity, and profitability. Firm mindset with a drive to find solutions to new problems. Strong analytical skills and detailed to project's requirements. Adaption well in groups and a willingness to understand the various roles played by fellow team members. Perform tests and find ways to eliminate bugs in the programs. Build interactive and dynamic websites. Experience with remote projects during master studies. Bachelor in Computer science (State University of New York) and Master in Software Engineering (Mälardalens högskola Västerås).

## Work experience

IT Support 2021 - 2021

## Leipzig International School

- IT Service Desk Help in the automation of processes
- Networking, Switches and Routing support
- Vitalization & Data Backups
- Update website
- Manage the wireless accounts

Researcher 2019 - 2021

### ESIT & University of Ulm

Development of a generic framework for mobile data sensing and mobile patient intervention for tinnitus patients.

Data analysis and articles publications

Development and manual software validation

#### PHP Developer - BlueScreen

2019 - 2019

\* Writing server-side web application logic \* Develop back-end components, connect the application with other web services, and support the front-end developers by integrating their work with the application. CI/CD processes . \* White Box testing of the final version

#### Technical Writer - Ericsson

2018 - 2019

\* Supporting documents to communicate complex and technical information \* Explain complex information in a clear and concise manner and working with the staff to ensure accuracy of product functionalities.

Contribute to the establishment and evolution of the digital organization.

Document several IT systems.



#### **Skills**

Methodology

Agile, Scrum, Test Driven Development

Testing

Jira, JUnit

**Databases** 

Firebase, Oracle, MS Access, MySQL

Languages

C++, C#, VB .Net, Java, Python, HTML/SQL/PHP, R

#### **Applications**

Weka, SPSS, Windows & Linux Environment, Active Directory, ArborText, GitLab, Dita XML, Baramundi, Ranorex, WireShark, Postman, Zammad, Jira, LogicMonitor, Obkio

## **Competencies**

- Project Management
- Troubleshooting
- Analytical skills
- Group work
- Network
- Coding
- Technical Support
- Quality Assurance
- Research in new technologies
- Multitasking
- Adapt in teams with different cultures

Languages

Perform automation testing when needed or required ( User acceptance test, end-to-end test)

Italian: B2 Spanish: B1

English: C1

Swedish: A1

French: A1 German: B1

## Certification

GDPR - DPO

Startup Winner

IT and DPO - qPharmetra Sweden

\* Cisco Meraki for cloud management, VPN networking, and application control. \* Configure switches \* Helped in building their intranet. \* Maintain Linux severs and do upgrades \* Backups \* IT support

#### Master thesis - Manual Tester

master thesis mandat reste

Accedo TV

Part of master thesis- Reviewing and analyzing system specifications. Executing test scripts and reviewing results for finding the effective variables for predicting faults in the code. Mobile, PC platforms.

Execute effective test plans and evaluation of product testing phases.

Testing for IP-based set-top boxes (different streaming services)

Optimization of test cases for mobile devices

Data analysis collected from the test logs (Jira)

Use WireShark and Postman

Documentation and troubleshoot of errors with different systems iOS, Android.

Lecturer - Albanian University Tirana

2015 - 2015

2018 - 2018

2017 - 2018

Lecturer and for one semester in Tirana and Berat for the subjects : Computer Architecture & Web Applications.

IT support - Albanian Psychologists Association

2014 - 2015

\* Made a website using in HTML/PHP/MySql and a documentation content management system using Java. \* Investigate faults in the network. \* Procure network equipment according to needs. \* Build dashboards, create reports and analyze data. \* Test with WireShark and PostMan their different existing software \* IT Support

Technical Support Specialist - Albanian Business Partner 2012 - 2014

- \*Meet with the client to determine customization requirements.
- \*Design and implement new network solution \*Facilitated network support for hospitals in Tirana for a software written in Java. \*
  Supported different troubleshoots within Windows systems. \*
  Customize routers. \* IT Support

#### Freelancer

Different websites for private companies using HTML/PHP/MySql. Helped several companies setting up: Office 365, Skype for Business, SharePoint, Active Directory

#### **Education**

## **Bachelor in Computer Science**

2010 - 2014

University of New York Tirana & State University of New York

Thesis: Hotel Booking Android application

# Master of Science in Software Engineering

2015 - 2017

Mälardalen University

Under Erasmus Mundus Scholarship

Thesis: Effectiveness of fault prediction

Download PDF - DIVA Portal

Thesis conducted at Accedo Broadband AB Stockholm

